Yaroslav Salmin

Email: yaroslavsalmin@gmail.com

Tel: 07748008458

Software engineer with an eye for UX, proficient in JavaScript, ReactJS, NextJS, Typescript, CSS3, styled-components, Sass, Redux, Automated unit and browser testing, Rest and GraphQL API, TDD, BDD, Git. Agile, CI/CD, AWS Lambda, S3, CloudFront.

Buckets of a SaaS, digital agency and FinTech experience developing, testing, documenting and deploying data-rich, data visualisation and e-commerce platforms.

Having had experience hiring and leading agile Scrum and Kanban multi-disciplined teams Yaroslav is a great team player however he is perfectly capable of managing time when working solo.

Yaroslav's client portfolio includes brands like Lloyds Bank Group, Satago, Volkswagen group, Wolseley, EvansHalshaw, Stratstone, Morrisons, The Ticket Factory (NEC Group), IPCentrum (de Banke Group) and Sensormatic by Johnson Controls.

EXPERIENCE

Satago, London — Lead Front End Engineer

Dec 2021 - Feb 2023

The new Front End platform delivery secured large funding from Lloyds Bank Group and opened doors for new opportunities.

I established a micro-frontends architecture in a monorepo. Code formatting and linting for consistency between teams.

Planned, prototyped and utilised user data in collaboration with the product and design teams to deliver business milestones on time.

Created a reusable library of UI components to bring consistency and cohesion. Some of the more complex dynamic components have reduced development costs by minimising duplicated code. Showcase in storybook stories deployed to a remote URL.

Introduced a design token system, which provided style consistency and facilitated a multi-tenant architecture.

Produced documentation for

- Local development
- File and folder structure
- Formatting and linting
- Component and page architecture
- Routing
- Global state management

Hired and led a front-end engineering team, and advised on code reviews and best practices.

Set up a Bitbucket Pipelines CI with a branch-based multi-environment deployment. AWS S3, Cloudfront and EdgeLambda.

Enhanced in-platform user communication by integrating a rich text editor. Text formatting, image and file upload, rich personalised snippets and templates. React, Remirror.

Client: ReactJS, Typescript, styled-components, Jest, Cypress, Rest and GraphQL API, Bitbucket. Jira, CI/CD BB Pipelines, Argo Workflows, AWS Lambda, S3, CloudFront.

API: GraphQl, Java Spring

Sensormatic by Johnson Controls (ShopperTrak), Solihull — Lead Contract Front End Developer

Aug 2018 - Dec 2021

Working in close collaboration across Product and Engineering Yaroslav worked on the visualisation of complex datasets, which allow retail giants to assess their sales performance and make business decisions.

He is used to working across 20+ widgets with various retail metrics like traffic, conversion, change and filters like group by, date range and compare period. He has experience with displaying complex tabular data and drawing multiline, pie, and scatter plot graphs using a library and writing bespoke code to achieve a business requirement.

As the complexity of data increases so does the need for scalable and optimised UI. As a lead software engineer, it was Yaroslav's responsibility to stay on top of code performance, test coverage and security vulnerabilities from pen test reports.

Working in CI/CD fashion allows for frequent releases. Therefore making sure the user is familiar with the released functionality is key to keeping them happy, and writing documentation becomes an essential part of every release.

Code documentation with JSDocs is as important and facilitates collaboration, a decrease in onboarding time and a reduction in bugs.

UI: ReactJS, Redux, Highcharts, Ag Grid, Jest, React testing library

API: Node Express and Java Spring

IPCentrum (de Banke Group), Solihull — Contract Front End Developer

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Simplifying intellectual property services through data visualisation and innovation.

The Ticket Factory (NEC Group), Birmingham — Contract Front End Developer

Feb 2017 - May 2018

Enabling event organisers to capture a wider audience through a cross-platform mobile app and push notifications.

Easywebstore, Derby — Contract Front End Developer

Mar 2016 - Jan 2017

Transforming the digital presence of Morrison's online florist e-commerce platform. Payment integration, delivery tracking and account management.

Key Parker, Lutterworth — *Front End Developer*

Apr 2015 - Feb 2016

Enhancing internal communication experience of VW group through developing a sophisticated drag & drop email builder. Streamlining of issuing energy performance certificates for Wolesley field engineers through a mobile app.

Pinewood Technologies, Birmingham — Front End Developer

Sep 2013 - Apr 2015

Improving the e-commerce presence of a major car retailer, ensuring a consistent approach to UI and codebase. Carry out the design and development of a rich user interface while focusing on the overall user experience.

Split the Bills Limited, Sheffield — Front End Developer Contract

Jul 2013 - Sep 2013

Helping tenants with managing house bills through consolidating individual accounts into a single portal.

Wegner Enterprises, Birmingham — Front End Developer Contract

Sep 2012 - Jun 2013

Responsible for user experience and user interface of the event comparison website.

Virgin Media Business, Birmingham — Front End Developer Contract

Aug 2012 - Sep 2012

Responsible for developing an HR web application.

Sigma Motors, St. Petersburg, Russia — Web Designer

Sep 2008 - Jul 2011

Visual design, marketing.

EDUCATION

$\textbf{University of Greenwich,} \ London-\textit{MA Web Design and Content Planning} \\$

Sep 2011 - Jun 2012

 $\textbf{St. Petersburg State Polytechnic University, St. Petersburg,} \ \textbf{St. Petersburg,} \ \textbf{St. Petersburg,} \ \textbf{Russia} - \textit{BSc Complex Security of Informatization Objects}$

Sep 2006 - Jun 2010